MUHAMAD HARITH ARASH BIN MUHAMAD HAKIM TAN

Coventry, United Kingdom | P: +4407877406030 | haritharash970123@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/harith-arash/ |

SUMMARY

An ambitious software engineer with two years of experience who has entered the IT world and is eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail, and excellent organisational skills. Has strong technical and problem-solving skills, as well as the ability to organise and be cautious in order to deliver a high-quality software product. Someone who is constantly eager to learn new things in



order to gain valuable knowledge and experience. Aim for a challenging working environment and be willing to invest passion and commitment to achieve the corporate vision.

PROJECT PORTFOLIO

GITHUB			
https://haritharash.github.io/MuhamadHarithArash/			

EDUCATION

Master of Computer	Bachelor of Science	Foundation In	Malaysian Certificate
Science	(Physics)	Science (PASUM)	of Education (SPM)
The University of Warwick	University of Malaya	Physical Science	Pure Science with
September 2022 – Present	August 2016 – January 2020	Jun 2015 – Jun 2016	Accoutancy
	CGPA: 3.78/4.00	CGPA: 4.00/4.00	Result: 8A2B

WORK EXPERIENCE

Servedeck Innovation Sdn Bhd [Mandrill Tech, Malaysia] – Smart Facilities Management Project Full-stack Software Developer Nov 2021 – Sept 2022

 Design a new module called subscription management to help internal team manage client licenses and categorise the users.

- Use external CSS libraries such as Angular Bootstrap, Angular Material and Angular Flex-Layout to create a responsive web sites.
- Proposed some ideas on the current modules to avoid confusion in the future development.
- Update database structure through liquidbase jhipster environment.
- Modulise existing features and implement limitation user interface based on the license client purchased.
- Auto deactivation users based on the license they purchased using cron expression.
- Limit the user creation from the client site to be based on the subscription.
- Develop multiple APIs to handle multiple request from web and mobile applications.
- Implement the design from Figma Design Tool to the actual website development.
- Coordinating with other developers on improvement user interface such as avoiding bugs and slowness of the application.

Prima Health System Sdn Bhd [Mandrill Tech, Malaysia] – Smart Medical Imaging Technology Project Full-stack Software Developer Aug 2020 – Nov 2021

- Develop a software to integrate with hospital HIS system and PACS for managing medical image data through Radiology Information System.
- Maintain and upgrade web application via Angular Framework, ReactJs, and Java Spring Boot.
- Able to utilise external open source library such as CornerstoneJs, VTKJs for 2D medical image data to 3D visualization.
- Research, design and organize multiple software programs.
- Perform QA inspection and identify any features in existing system to enhance and proposing ideas to upgrade.
- Deploy compiled products via Putty Terminal and Docker containers.
- Implement Gitlab workspace environment for updating features and fixing issues.
- Basic management knowledge of Cloud Native Application Architecture such as Amazon Console.

Top Glove Corporation (Internship) - Klang, Selangor, Malaysia

Quality Assurance Researcher

July 2019 - Oct 2019

- Trainee as a Quality Assurance Researcher to develop a software that able to collect inspection data more efficient and flexible.
- Build a platform (Google Form) to standardise the collection of data using QR code and mini-app for easy launch through worker's phone.
- Collaborated with engineer to provide data analysis for report issuance.
- Followed quality standards and procedures to minimize errors and maximize test quality.
- Assist engineer in performing QA testing in terms of execution of QA test, collecting and compiling test data.

PROFESSIONAL SIDE PROJECTS

Simulation of Nuclear Transmutation

Statistical predictive behavior of nuclear transmutation process

- Construct and develop model for the nuclear interaction of gases using C++ language and CERN Geant4 package manager.
- Build and design code to execute an open sources simulation software in Linux OS.
- Predict and visualize data of interaction using Python ROOT-Data Analysis Framework.
- Data collection and predictive pattern using Python with external scientific methods.

Web Development Programming

Web Developer (ReactJS)

- A small project that use languages such as ReactJs to develop front end application.
- Split every input characters based on vowel, consonant, number and special characters.
- Basic handling of database with MySQL.
- Linking the architecture with the database such as PostgreSQL.

Data Engineer (Python)

- A small analysis project using police brutality cases data that occured in the united states.
- Use Jupyter notebook as a workspace for data presentation and providing insight to the number of cases
 occured
- Use external libraries such as folium, pandas, numpy to map every data to the geographical data.
- Provide an overview and interactive visualizations for viewers.

SKILLS

HARD SKILLS:

- Python: Familiar with the standard concept, control structure of Python, algorithm and programming elements such as variables, conditional statements and looping. Able to do data cleaning, data preprocessing and analysis with NumPy and Pandas, and a little bit data visualization with Seaborn.
- **SQL [Postgresql & Mariadb]:** Understand and familiar on how to write SQL queries and SQL JOINs in order to manage data that are stored in a relational database management system.
- **Microsoft Office:** Proficient in Microsoft Office (Word and PowerPoint). Have knowledge in doing Data Analysis using Excel.
- Java Spring Framework: Familiar with Java 8, functional ascpects, Spring Framework, Spring Boot and Spring Integration.
- Angular & ReactJs: Have a decent knowledge with front-end framework, integrate with external libraries or communicate with other applications.
- C & C++: Knowledge in simulation using Geant4 (CERN simulative tools), syntax for visualization.
- **HTML,CSS,Javascript**: Experience in using standard structure tags or components, different style classes and implement logical flow of the web development.
- Docker, AWS Console, Glthub & Gitlab: Manage tickets and deployed products with external softwares.
- NodeJs & Typescript: Knowledge in startup app using Node interface such as Jhipster project or node project.

SOFT SKILLS AND LEADERSHIP:

- **Teamwork:** Love to work and participate in group to accomplish project objectives. Tends to contribute something and give significant impact to the team.
- Collaboration: Tends to collaborate with others in doing things that I found difficult to be solved alone. By
 doing this, it helps me to expand my network and capable of solving the problems in a proper manner.
- **Problem solving and analytical thinking:** Able to identify and define problems, extracting key-information, test and verify the root cause of the problems in order to design workable solutions.
- Results- Driven: A results oriented person where I constantly set goals and plans to achieve it within the designated deadlines and meeting those goals give me the real feel of satisfaction.
- Planning, Organizing and Prioritizing: Learn on how to prioritize work by identifying the end goal, objectives, create a checklist and also consistent and focus on the big picture so that I feel motivated.

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Reserve Officer Training Unit TLDM (ROTU)

- Participate ROTU for 3 years and commissioned as 2nd Lieutenant under Pasukan Simpanan Sukarela TLDM a volunteer Unit of the Royal Malaysian Navy.
- Fully experience with the culture of the royal navy and fully committed to complete any task given by the superiors.
- Able to work under pressure and eager to learn something new in order to face real world problems and find the solution.

Member of Physics Society, University of Malaya (PERFUM)

- Monitor & assist the student body projects for student empowerment.
- Establish and implement continuous standard in organizational of documents.
- Participate every events held by the club and become a committee in multiple projects.

Student Exchange Programme, Gachon University, Seongnam, Republic of South Korea

- Act as a communication channel between UM students and International Student Centre management.
- Facilitate the program preparation for UM students throughout semester.

REFEREES

Dr. Siti Fairus Binti Abdul Sani	Mr Chong Kok Weng
Senior Lecturer	Consultant
University of Malaya	Mandrill Tech
s.fairus@um.edu.my	kokweng.chong@mandrill.com.my